[Music]
welcome everyone my name is Austine and
I'm going to tell you what's new with
the contoso demo tool in this release
and the generation and maintainability
of demo data if you have you know used
the old way of generating demo data um
and extending demo data with the rapid
start packages you will be pretty
familiar with some of these pains and
why we decided to go this route um as
you may know this packages were like a
big monolith we either bring everything
in or you bring nothing so if you had to
do a demo about small feature um you had
to bring the whole shebang with you uh
and if you had to extend it maybe you
wanted to bring a new feature to demo
together with that one or maybe you
wanted to uptake some of the changes
that we made to demo data um then it was
very painful because you have to
regenerate that package you can just
just modify it or extend it
easily same thing with um translations
if you had to do this demo in a
different country in a different
language you needed to create a copy of
that package with everything translated
which then will mean that it will
multiply and then it will be much more
difficult to actually maintain and
uptake new changes to them you have to
do it in many many
places because it's file based there was
no very good story about version and
Source
control um and we didn't support
historical data as part of these
packages so you needed posted documents
to be part of your demo you had to find
different ways to do it with some
postprocessing after the fact so many
partners will end up with something akin
to this right many different versions of
the same package maybe the first one
works very well with the demo number one
the second one works very well with the
demo number two but they don't mix very
well together and you have yet another
package for each of the languages that
you actually want to demo this on so
this was very very difficult and costly
to
maintain so when we designed this new
tool we kept all of these things in mind
so we wanted to break down this monolith
package so how would we do that well we
we broke it down into these different
modules following the the name spaces in
basap and you can install this
independently uh some of them maybe are
completely independent so you can just
install this a small piece to do a demon
know
sustainability um but you can Define
also dependencies among them so if you
want to demo something in the sales area
and you're requireed to have finances
set up and inventory set up uh then you
can Define dependencies among them and
the tool will handle the installation if
you need to you want to install um this
particular module for your demo it will
pick up all everything on the on the
tree of dependencies and install it
automatically for
you we wanted to because it's we wanted
to solve this issue with source source
control and versioning to make it easier
to extend and maintain and go back to
previous versions and things like this
we just made it code so you can see in
here that it's much easier to read we
have a code unit that is about creating
a unit of measure and then you can
clearly see what is being created in
there and you can create more and expand
it easily um because it's code it also
brings other benefits as well right like
we talked about the translation before
now you can handle the translation the
same way you handle um in in your
applications so use a translation file
and you can much easier to do this
instead of having to maintain very very
different versions it also natively
means that this goes into Source control
this is actually in in GitHub in a app
extensions you can actually see the
whole code of this tool and the demo
data we generate you can read it you can
come and suggest some changes
improvements find tell us that we have a
bug or something like this and
eventually we want to move all of this
code into BC apps and make it fully open
source so anyone can come and contribute
you can bring your own modules in into
into demo data generation you can fix
issues you can solve that problem that
has been bagging you for a while in in
the demo data that we ship um also that
story with the historical data we we
broke down if you go into one of these
modules and you will see all of these
different layering um we have you can
develop independently the setup data for
the module the the master data that that
defines this this feature but also the
transactions and the historical data so
you can e spand those individually if
you want you know more volume data or um
if you want to do you need posted
documents and uh you can clearly just
create the historical data for those and
you can do cool things because it's it's
code now right so if you for example
need that this demo requires that the
historical data FS within fits within
the same quarter or the same fiscal year
you can just do that you can write the
code and it will continually follow
follow you so if you have to do this
demo two years from now to a c customer
the data will just be ready for you
within the same fiscal quarter instead
of like being
obsoleted that is basically it that's
what we did we managed to break down
this monolith we managed to make
everything code so it's easier to
develop and expand and extend and
upgrade and all of these things so we
want to now we're working on the next
steps where do we go from here so we
would love to hear from you and actually
this is already available as part of 20
5.3 because we needed it to unblock
another great feature flexible update
management that you can see in this
launch event I totally recommend to go
and check that video and uh we look
forward for you to go and play with this
try it around add it to your pipelines
see how you will push it to production
and let us know how we you know make
this even better together um so reach
out to us through the usual channels
social media Viva and whatever else we
can we can talk to each other uh that
was it thank you very much and have a
lovely day